<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Hello my name is TheDiamondPicks. I am a software developer with experience in Java, HTML, PHP, VB.NET, CSS, Bootstrap and Bukkit. I enjoy programming and I currently work for fun and therefore I do work for free. Feel free to contact me if you wish to have work done (Within the realms of reason (e.g. No large MC minigames!)).</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 07:39:52 +1300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 07:39:52 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mojang &amp; Multiplayer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forewarning this is a rant. It may be long but I hope it gets my point across. I have absolutly nothing but respect for Mojang as they are a pretty awesome company with awesome people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiplayer is a huge aspect of Minecraft. It is actually what makes many of “veteran” Minecrafter’s stay in the game.
But Mojang barely supports it. All it does is provides a basic multiplayer infrastructure for the “Modded” servers to base themselves off&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t always like this. Back in 2012 Mojang purchased CraftBukkit, the then most popular Minecraft server software. Mojang then
hired the four primary developers (EvilSeph, Tahg, Dinnerbone and Grum). They specifically hired these developers to work on their
new multiplayer plugin API (Application Program Interface) called &lt;a href=&quot;http://minecraft.gamepedia.com/Plugin_API&quot;&gt;Workbench&lt;/a&gt; (You can find the original post &lt;a href=&quot;https://mojang.com/2012/02/minecraft-team-strengthened/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).
But unfortunatly these plans never really came to fruition and eventually EvilSeph and Tahg left mojang (Seph returned to Bukkit and Tahg quit Minecraft altogether).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast foward to 2014 and most people had largely forgotton this. Workbench was still unfinished and the GitHub and dev.minecraft.net domain had been
taken down. Bukkit &lt;a href=&quot;https://bukkit.org/threads/bukkit-its-time-to-say.305106/&quot;&gt;had just been shut down by its lead dev&lt;/a&gt; but then it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://storify.com/lukegb/the-tale-of-bukkit-for-minecraft-1-8&quot;&gt;revived&lt;/a&gt; (Note this contains out of date information regarding Minecraft 1.8. However the ownership parts still apply).
But then the Bukkit project was hit with a DMCA (You can view the original notice &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20141217165734/http://dl.bukkit.org/dmca/notification.txt&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).
Naturally this caused outrage that Mojang would apparently sanction a DMCA that took down the biggest Minecraft server software. 
Then Mojang &lt;a href=&quot;https://bukkit.org/threads/mojang-and-the-bukkit-project.309715/&quot;&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; saying it was misrepresented.
The future of Minecraft Servers looked bleak. Aside from porjects liked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glowstone.net/&quot;&gt;Glowstone&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spongepowered.org/&quot;&gt;Sponge&lt;/a&gt; which were far from completion
there was no full support for 1.8 and the only 1.8 compatible server software was also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spigotmc.org/threads/dmcad.28536/&quot;&gt;affected&lt;/a&gt;.
But then Spigot decided &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spigotmc.org/threads/1-8-progress-check.32792/&quot;&gt;to take on&lt;/a&gt; the huge task that was updating to Minecraft 1.8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like it has absolutly nothing to do with Mojang but it has a great deal to do with it. Firstly Mojang has a sort of
obligation to server owners and server software developers as they are the ones who make Minecraft even more successful.
For example Hypixel has approximatly 7 million unique players whereas Minecraft has around 20 million at the time of writing. This
equates to 33% of the Minecraft community has logged on to Hypixel. This includes those “noobs” who can’t log on to a server.
But many people may say that Mojang does support servers in the form of the Vanilla Server Software. But this is invalid in 2 ways.
Firstly Vanilla Minecraft is laggy and is not extendable whatsoever (e.g. No plugins = Very little moderation tools and minigames).
And all network larger than 100 players would be extremely laggy and basically suck. Therefore people use 3rd party software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;chart_div&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SeargeDP/status/604206757108420608&quot;&gt;SeargeDP on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the chart above Spigot is by far the most popular Minecraft server software. But this graph does not
include servers that only restart and don’t stop and servers with snooper enabled. So in the real world it would be quite different.
The other thing that could be deemed as sligtly unfair is that the server types are divided up into the different types so to get a
better idea of what it is like see the chart bellow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;chart_div1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see the vast majority of servers run something other than Vanilla. This shows Mojang should do something more. But
unfortunatly that is unlikely due to a realatively new service called Minecraft Realms. By hosting it on there own servers
Mojang gets a tidy profit from every Realms server that is not a trial so this means they are hesitant to provide a offical
solution as they are worried it will eat into their profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I believe is not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of Realms users are people who:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can’t afford a server.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For them hosting a server is to complex and takes more time up than playing on the server.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Or they just want to host a few adventure maps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Mojang did indeed develop a server software these types of people would likely not use it and continue with Realms.
Some might also argue that the MC devs are focused on making the game better. But my argument to this is that Mojang can easily
hire these people or even recruit them via Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not everything involves Mojang making an API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mojang could actually has the power to give Bukkit and Spigot &lt;em&gt;offical&lt;/em&gt; permission to use Minecraft server code or at least allow them to use it
but force users to also download vanilla so that they are not distributing it with the open source code. This would truly make
Wolveress’ claims unfounded. The other solution is to provide all server software developers who request mappings to have them.
Which is essentially what they did when they aquired Bukkit’s core team for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at least one of the things in this blog post are done then Minecraft multiplayer will be truly awesome. Because what’s better than
playing on a custom built server with complex minigames which add something substantial to Minecraft with friends?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read this whole thing you deserve a cookie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~TheDiamondPicks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;ps-kudos-to-google-for-the-charts-code&quot;&gt;P.S: kudos to Google for the charts code.&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 09:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        <link>/rants/2016/01/04/mojang-and-multiplayer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/rants/2016/01/04/mojang-and-multiplayer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to My Website</title>
        <description>
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello world!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hello World&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;player&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sendMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ChatColor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;RED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal website. I hope you find it helpful and informative. Some of you may remember the 1 page template horror that was my previous site so I have completely revamped it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t resist posting specs of the website so here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jekyll System that proceeses the header and footer and makes them appear on every page along with universal styling rules.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jekyll again which allows me to post blog posts in the amazing Markdown format and then automagically syncing them with my local site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Git enables me to quickly commit changes to the GitHub repo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;GitHub pages which a) Gives me free hosting and a free .github.io domain but also b) allows me to commit changes quickly and effiently.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on to the stuff you can see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TEMPLATED/Cloud Canon’s Linear design which I have based by website off of.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Font Awesome which is a free to use font image tool (Like Windings) that works awesomely for things like the globe icons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Not to mention countless pieces of code that has been used in making this site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless thanks for visiting and have a happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
        <link>/site/2015/12/29/welcome-to-thediamondpicks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/site/2015/12/29/welcome-to-thediamondpicks.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>site</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
